

Mohammed Adib Islam

143, East Tejturi Bazaar Tejgaon Dhaka - 1215 **E-mail:** adib.islam113@gmail.com **Website:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/adib-

islam-436aa6164/

Phone: +8801682020111

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I want to build a career in a field where I will be able to utilize my education, skills to the full potential and create an impact within the Industry. Results motivate me so I take out the full potential outcome from a task. However, my experience as a business developer in an RMG factory made me realize technical knowledge is not enough to take you to the greater stage of your profession. The combination of Engineering and management seems just the right way to start. And the fact that I am ready to do the extra work to get myself connected to the business by getting involved with administrative work makes me a prominent candidate for any project.

KEY FIELDS OF INTEREST

- Heat & Mass Transfer
- Solid Mechanics
- Power Plant Engineering
- Project Management
- Research & Development

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

LEED Green Associate Workshop Certification (2018)

Training by: Prof. Dr. Muhammad Riazul Hamid, USGBC Faculty, LEED AP (BD+C), EDGE Expert, CEO, Green Professionals & GreenProBD.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SQ Group

Jan 2019 — July 2019

Management Trainee

Lingerie, first divergence of merchandise by SQ, is at a nascent stage. The company is named fittingly as SQ Birichina Ltd, with the meaning of Birichina being 'naughty' in Italian – a witty representation of the attire's sensitivity. Birichina was established in 2008 with a capacity of only six flexible modules in partnership with Quantum Clothing Ltd, a UK based conglomerate and dedicated supplier to Marks & Spencer.

Job Responsibilities:

- Development of Fabric Tracking System
- Management of shipment
- Analysis of Fabric Backlog
- Communication with Suppliers
- Analysis of fabric Tech department
- Responsible for heat seal department
- Implication of 5s throughout the factory

Mohammed Adih Islam

B.Sc in Mechanical Engineering

Nov 2014 — Mar 2019

Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology

CGPA: 3.10

Accomplished

1. "EXPERIMENTAL INVESTIGATION OF POOL BOILING HEAT TRANSFER ENHANCEMENT OVER CYLINDRICAL TUBES UNDER DIFFERNET WETTING CONDITIONS" (Thesis)

Thesis Objective:

- To investigate the pool-boiling heat transfer enhancement
- To observe the nature of nucleate region of pool boiling

2. "INCLINED SURFACE ADAPTION SYSTEM: INCLINED SURFACE ADAPTION SYSTEM" (**Project**)

Thesis Statement:

The objective of this project is to detect the angular variation when the prototype car goes to inclined surface & maintain the container parallel to the surface. By using MPU-6050 sensor & Servo Motor, this calibration has been done with the help of Arduino. Two Motors have been used to run the wheel. Bread board has been used to set connection between sensor, Servo motor, wheels & battery.

This project is a Microcontrollerbased project which has been done with the help of basic PID controlling system. Proportional & Differential factors were added to the system. Integration has not been used in this project because the calibration method for Integrating is more complicated & the code for this system is too large.

Higher Secondary Certification

2012 - 2014

Dhanmondi Ideal College

GPA: 5.00

Secondary School Certification

2011 — 2012

Tejgaon Government High School

GPA: 4.75

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- MATLAB
- Solid Works
- MS Office
- Wordpress

INTERPERSONAL ANALYSIS

- Hard and passionate worker.
- Opportunity Seeker.
- Creative & Confident.
- Disciplined & Enthusiast.
- Able to work under pressure and to get the job done by deadline.
- Welcoming to uncertain and new situations.
- Adaptive to new environment.
- Team player
- Willingness to Learn
- Positive Attitude
- Analytical Thinker

Mohammed Adib Islam

INTERESTS

- Reading & Writing
- Body Workout
- Self Development
- Podcast

REFERENCE

Name: Anjan Goswami

Designation: Assistant Professor

Cell: +8801913776863

Email: anjan05me@gmail.com

Name: Prof.Dr.Dewan Hasan Ahmed

Designation: Professor Cell: +88029897339

Email: dhahmed@hotmail.com

Mohammed Adib Islam